nutritionexpress.com 2004-08-05

# Nutrition Express Privacy Statement

The privacy of Nutrition Express online customers is treated with utmost respect. The personally identifiable information on you and your purchases will not be sold, rented or given away to any other company or agency without your explicit permission. This document should answer any questions you may have regarding user privacy and our web site. _(Please see our_ [Terms of Use Agreement](http://www.nutritionexpress.com/pls/ne/nut_exp?ID=a87030505026000&treq=ts&mid=&sub=&itm=&dgp=&pg=) _for information on use and liability.)_

**Information Collection and Use**  
Nutrition Express is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, rent or give this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. Nutrition Express collects information from our users at several different points on our web site. 

**Ordering** We request information from the user during our order process. Here a user must provide contact information (such as name and address) and may provide financial information (such as a credit card number). This information is used for billing purposes and order fulfillment. If we have trouble processing an order, the contact information is used to get in touch with the user. _(See also Additional Uses and Choice/Opt-in below.)_

**Cookies** A cookie is a piece of data stored on a user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. A single cookie is used on this site in order to help us to keep track of your shopping cart. If you choose to place an order with us, the cookie will be removed when your order is placed. Otherwise, it will expire 24 hours after your initial visit to our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback is that the user will lose their shopping cart if they leave the site for any reason before completing the order process. 

**Log Files** We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

**Information Sharing**  
We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and/or advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. 

We use a credit card processing company to bill users for purchases. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purpose. 

We occasionally make portions of our customer data available to carefully screened companies that offer products or services you may enjoy. Your customer data/information will not be shared except at your request (opt-in). You will have the ability to opt-in during the checkout procedure. _(See Additional Uses and Choice/Opt-in below.)_

We do not share, rent or sell customer email addresses to any third party. 

**Link Issues**  
This web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Nutrition Express, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

**Security**  
This website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card numbers), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as those that encompass our order process, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers (such as Netscape Navigator or Microsoft Internet Explorer) becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are "just surfing." 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, customer service representatives and order processing employees) are granted access to personally identifiable information. All employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are kept in a securely locked environment. 

If you have any questions about security at our web site, you can write to [webmaster@nutritionexpress.com](mailto:webmaster@nutritionexpress.com). 

**Additional Uses & Choice/Opt-in**  
**Telephone Contact** Users may be contacted by phone if there is a problem or question about an order that they have placed. Also, from time to time, we may phone a small percentage of our customers for input on how to improve our service and product selection. 

**Email Contact** From time to time, we send emails to our customers which may include product updates, special offers, notice of web site updates, etc. You will not be included in our email promotions mailing list without your express consent. Further, each email message sent will provide instructions for removing your address from future mailings. Email solicitations will be from Nutrition Express only; we do not share, rent or sell our email lists with any third party. _(See Choice/Opt-in below.)_

**Choice/Opt-in** During the checkout procedure, you will have the ability to opt in to our email list. You will also be given the opportunity to receive postal mailings from third parties. You will not be included in any list unless it is at your request. You can remove your name at any time from either list by contacting Customer Care at 1-800-754-8000 or by sending an email to [customercare@nutritionexpress.com](mailto:customercare@nutritionexpress.com). 

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, notification will be linked from our homepage to the new policy so that our users are always up-to-date on what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances (if any) we disclose it. Users will be notified via email and presented with an opportunity to opt-out should we decide to use information in a manner that is inconsistent with the way in which it was collected. 

|  |  | August Internet Specials  
---  
Save 40% or more online this month on our complete line of these popular brands:  
|   

|   

---  

Questions? 1-800-338-7979  
Copyright 2000-2004 Nutrition Express Corporation. All rights reserved. 

Information provided on this site is solely for informational purposes only. It is not a substitute for professional medical advice. Do not use this information for diagnosing or treating a health problem or disease, or prescribing of any medications or supplements. Only your healthcare provider should diagnose your healthcare problems and prescribe treatment. 

None of our statements or information, including health claims, articles, advertising or product information have been evaluated or approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA). The products or ingredients referred to on this site are not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any disease. Please consult your healthcare provider before starting any supplement, diet or exercise program, before taking any medications or receiving treatment, particularly if you are currently under medical care. Make sure you carefully read all product labeling and packaging prior to use. If you have or suspect you may have a health problem, do not take any supplements without first consulting and obtaining the approval of your healthcare provider. 

We cannot be held responsible for typographical, system or application errors.
